In the project files, I've written this Event Listener.
我在项目文件中编写了这个事件监听器
So I'm listening on the body for a keypress.
在 body 上监听 keypress 事件
Then I'm going to log the message removing first child.
然后输出消息 removing first child
I'll look through the DOM,
在 DOM 中查找
for this element with this ID.
具有这个 ID 的元素
I'll find its first child and I'll remove it.
查找它的第一个子项 删除该子项
Let's switch over to the browser and see this in action.
回到浏览器中并看看运行效果
Here I am in the browser,
我打开了浏览器
and let's find that element.
查找该元素
It is contain-all.
它是 contain-all
And it contains all of the visible content on the page.
包含页面上所有的可见内容
Now one thing I want to point out is that div tools
要提醒的一点是
has an Event Listeners panel right here.
开发者工具在这里有个 Event Listeners 面板
Now if I click on it, it will show us all of
点击该面板后 它将显示
the registered Event Listeners for the selected item.
所选项的所有已注册事件监听器
As we can see, there are no Event Listeners for this div with contain-all ID.
可以看出 这个 ID 为 contain-all 的 div 没有事件监听器
I can click the Ancestors check box,
我可以点击 Ancestors 复选框
to see all of the ancestors to this element.
看看该元素的所有祖先
And we can see that the body has a keypress listener.
可以看到 body 有一个 keypress 监听器
Hovering over this section here provides us a Remove button,
将光标悬停在此部分上方将显示一个 Remove 按钮
which will remove the Event Listener just for this time or session.
该按钮将删除这一次或这个会话的事件监听器
Reloading the page will bring it back. Alright let's test this out.
重新加载页面将恢复该监听器 我们测试一下
So I'm going to click over here so that the page has focus and I'm going to press a key.
点击此处 使该页面具有焦点 然后按下一个按键
And this element has updated.
这个元素更新了
Now watch this header. And I'm going to press another key,
注意这个标题 我将再按一个按键
and I'm going to keep pressing keys.
继续按下按键
And we can see that
可以看到
each first child element is getting deleted every single time I press a key.
每次按下一个按键 每个第一个子元素都被删除了
And last but not least.
删除最后一个
So, that's really cool.
很酷
Another cool thing is that the Event Listeners panel will let us see
另一个比较酷的是 Event Listeners 面板
where the function was defined that actually runs.
将告诉我们实际运行的函数是在何处定义的
So, if I choose this arrow right here and bring this down a bit.
展开这个图标 往下拉一拉
This handler here is the function that will run in response to the keypress.
这个处理程序将是对按键做出响应并运行的函数
And I can right click this and choose show function definition.
在此处右击并选择 show function definition
Doing that will bring us over to
这样就会转到 Sources 面板
the Sources panel and will show us where that function was defined.
显示该函数的定义位置
It was in app js and here is that function.
定义位于 app.js 中 该函数在此处
We can see that the cursor is placed right at the beginning of the function.
可以看到光标放在了该函数的起始之处